

# TINU ANAND SINGH

©+91 9611449026 tinu14@gmail.com

# linkedin.com/in/tinu-singh/



# Summary

A Certified Scrum Master having 6 years of IT professional experience with a keen ability to understand and build complex systems and focusing relentlessly at removing impediments for scrum teams in order to deliver customer-centric product and features.

#### Education

Masters of Computer Applications (MCA) - Christ University, 2014 -2017

### **Professional Experience**

Hudini | Project Delivery Manager/ Scrum Master, 2022

- Involved in mentoring and managing the remote cross-functional team of 22 members and coaching Agile methodologies and scrum practices at organizational level
- Built global client relationship by participating in product launch kickoff meetings, and actively participating in sprint review meetings to capture the closely understand the customer needs and feedback on every sprint progress.

### Halodoc | Scrum Master / Project Manager 2021 – to 2022

- Extensively led in the *Sprint Planning* and *daily scrums* to push continuous improvement in the sprints, *and motivate team* to align with sprint goals.
- Effectively removed impediments and advised process improvements for 3 scrum teams resulting in team productivity thereby reducing the turn-around time to resolve customer complaints within 24 hours.
- Actively helped the product owner in product backlog refinement and ensuring the Product Requirements Documents (PRD) completion before the sprint planning thereby increasing team velocity by 20%

#### Neutrinos (Johannesburg, South Africa) | Senior Software Engineer / Scrum Master, 2019 –2020

- Led a product team of 8 developers and revamped engineering processes implementing weekly code sprints, *agile methodologies*, and code reviews to build a web application for automobile insurance sales.
- Enhanced existing product features resulting in a reduction of operational costs by ~25%.

#### **Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solutions** | Associate Software Engineer, 2017 – 2018

- Planned the *product roadmap* of an *IoT solution* for the OEM's real-time tracking of shipment; automating the *inventory forecasting* and shipment planning efficiency by 2days.
- Wrote user stories, user acceptance criteria, developed mockups and workflows for new features and functionalities

#### IBM India Pvt Ltd | Procurement Specialist, 2012 –2014

- Directed 2 SAP training for 30 new recruits, resulting in 90% of trainees being immediately project-deployable.
- Identified gaps in the supply chain process, and hence increasing revenue by \$130,00 in a quarter.

#### **Key Skills**

Agile Framework – Scrum & Kanban | Agile Project Management | Git/Gitlab | Jira | Confluence | Smartsheet | Microsoft Office Tools | SQL | Python | Solution Architecture – AWS | DevOps Foundations - AWS

# **Awards & Achievements**

- Professional Scrum Master Certification Scrum.org, 2022
- PMP Training PMI Institute, 2022
- AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate 2021
- Certified Scrum Product Owner Scrum Alliance 2020
- IOT Research Paper Publication Journal of Computer Science, 2018
- German language A1 and A2 level certification Robert Bosch, 2018
- Secured 1st position in IT Manager as well as IT Quiz at a National Level IT fest competing with 40+ universities, 2016
- Awarded with the Best Performer of the Year at IBM India Pvt Ltd, 2012